SAM TAHMASBI

Ottawa, Ontario samantahmasbii@gmail.com +15149925101

SUMMARY

A combination of web development and design background with strong computer and customer service skills. Known as a hard worker who willingly takes additional responsibility while juggling multiple projects. Expert in web development and graphic design.

SKILLS

• Excellent computer skills • Design consulting • Client relations • Excellent communication skills • Ability to work in a team • Comfortable working in a fast-paced environment. • Graphic design skills • Development and organization of CAD libraries and projects • Proficiency in engineering concepts • Problem-solving • Detail-oriented • Excellent mathematical and statistical skills

COMPUTER SKILLS

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES AND LIBRARIES: • CSS • HTML • JavaScript • JQuery

• Node.js • Express • Bootstrap • React • Wordpress

<u>DESIGNING TOOLS:</u> • Wordpress • 3dsMax • Revit • AutoCAD • Photoshop • 20\20 design • ArchiCAD

MS OFFICE: • Microsoft Excel • Microsoft Word • Powerpoint

LANGUAGE: English (Fluent), French(Beginner), Russian (Fluent), Persian (Fluent)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Web Developer Jan 2019 to present Globit- Remotely

Responsibilities:

- Wrote and edited web code using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and JQuery.
- Managed and maintained client websites (Retail, Commercial, Advertising)
- Developed and managed Ecommerce websites
- Created custom web pages from themes
- Created and edited original graphics and or stock photos.
- Designed a web presence from initial concept
- Created UI/UX design
- · Published web content online
- · Created mobile-friendly sites
- Maintained website by updating content, implementing new technology and monitoring performance
- Validated site by testing JavaScript, CSS3, and HTML5 codes to ensure cross-platform compatibility
- Wrote About Page biography, designed and shaped graphics, corrected image problems, and formatted company logos for the Web
- Developed a user-friendly architecture by programming site navigation, social media links/widget and organizing site content into a logical catalogues
- Consulted with the client to outline website goals, illustrate wireframe, and site functionality

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE INCLUDES

Branch Manager Sep 2018 to April 2019

Nazeran Exchange - Toronto, ON

CAD designer Jul 2014 to Aug 2017

(IOEC) Iranian Offshore Engineering and Construction Company Tehran

EDUCATION

Graduate Certificate in Web Development Sep 2017- March 2018

Concordia University

Master's degree in design Sep 2012 to Jun 2014

National Aviation University

Bachelor's degree in architecture Sep 2006 to Jul 2010

National Aviation University

Diploma in Computer Science (Post-secondary diploma) Aug 2005 to 2006

European University

Licences: G Driving License. Clean driving record

Portfolio Available Upon Request Reference Available Upon Request